Welcome back on this Friday Eve to the Amanda Seals Show.
I am Nels, and it is time for the Big Up Letdown.
Who are you saluting today, Amanda?
Yusef Salaam, one of the exonerated Central Park Five, and he is running for office.
He announced his candidacy for a highly coveted city council seat in Harlem, uptown, in the 9th District on Saturday.
If y'all don't know, and you were living under a rock, Salam, and four other minors, they were all black and Latino.
They were wrongfully convicted and imprisoned for the rape of a white jogger in Central Park in 1989.
And just to also add, Donald Trump took out a full-page ad calling for them to face the death penalty,
only to see how many years, years, years, and years later, in 2002, a judge vacated the convictions of all of them,
saying that the theory of the case was no longer valid.
So they were all exonerated.
Now, here's the thing, though.
I just want to point this out.
He won, like, $7 million in the suit that they filed against the city for being wrongfully committed, right?
So wrongfully convicted, okay?
But the woman that he's running against, when she found out that he was going to run, she said,
I think we have enough millionaires in office already.
That is part of the problem.
Sis, I can't get with you on this one.
I can't get with you on this one, okay?
Because it's a different thing when you win $7 million because you were wrongfully convicted as a teenager of a crime and spent all that time.
And I can't get with you on this one.